Guide to the Cosmetics Trade Samples and Sachet collection, 1890s-1930s RL.11349
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Unidentified, 37
  - Conzatti's Gem Complexion Powder, undated (Box 1, Item RL11349-0070)
    No manufacturer information. Text: "Trial Package Conzatti's Gem Complexion Powder, (Pure White) Being purely Vegetable and Medicated, it renders the Skin delicately soft and smooth, and imparts a natural brilliancy to the complexion without deleterious results. It has no equal in the market, and is the LADIES' FAVORITE. TRY IT AND YOU WILL USE NO OTHER."
- Vanity Fair Company, 38
  - Vanity Fair Face Powder, Flesh., 1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0071)
    The Vanity Fair Company, Memphis Tenn. Front image of Dorothy Dalton with text "Beauty's Aid/To the Vanity Fair Co. most cordially Dorothy Dalton." Text on reverse promotes range of Vanity Fair cosmetics.
- W.D. Freeman Perfumer, 39
  - Freeman's Medicated Face Powder, 1900s-1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0072)
    W.D. Freeman Perfumer, New York and Cincinnati. Text: "Invisible--harmless as dew--conceals blemishes. Made in White, Pink, and Cream or Brunette shades, the color of this envelop designating the shade of the powder within." Application instructions on reverse.
- William E. Hagan, creator, 40
  - Hagan's Magnolia Balm, 1900s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0073)
    Creation of William E. Hagan, of Troy NY. Rights transferred several times during the late 19th century. Portion of the poem "Five Sisters" by Kate Greenaway (1846-1901) included. Sales agent C. Brown Druggist, Milton Pa.
- Wrisley Perfumer, 41
  - Wrisley's San Toy Talcum, 1910s-1920s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0074)
    Wrisley Perfumer, Chicago. Slogan on front "Ask for Wrisley's" and "Absolutely Perfect Highly Perfumed." Text on reverse "Free Sample Penalty for Sale $500.00."
  - Wrisley's San Toy Talcum, 1910s-1920s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0075)